Guide to the Drama Library, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Drama Library, Yale University, records
1926-2009
RU 1086
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
2.75
(4 boxes)
The materials consist of correspondence, gift records, accession records, and annual reports.
Yale University. Drama Library
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 32-D (YRG32-D), Records of Yale school and departmental libraries and collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transferred from the Drama Library, 2009.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Biographical / Historical
The Drama Library began in 1925 when the Department of Drama (later School of Drama) was founded by George Pierce Baker. During most of its history it was located in the University Theatre building at 222 York Street. In August of 2008 it joined the collections housed in the Haas Family Arts Library.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of correspondence, gift records, accession records, and annual reports.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Academic libraries -- Departmental libraries; Performing arts libraries; Theater libraries; Yale University. Drama Library; Yale University. Library
- Drama Library records, 1926-2009; Accession 2010-A-001; 2
  Conditions Governing Access
  Materials older than 35 years are open; remainder of material restricted 35 years from date of creation.
  Scope and Contents
  The materials consist of accession records, annual reports, and correspondence.
  - Annual Reports and Statistics
    - 1928-1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1976-1990 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1990-1998 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1998-2008 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - ACCESSION LIST BOOKS, 1926-2009
    - 1926 (1-650) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1926 Aug-1940 Jun (1-7000) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1941 Feb-1961 Jan (7001-12000) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1961 Jan-1972 Feb (12001-16900) (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1972 Feb-1978 Feb (16901-20800) (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1978 Feb-1986 May (20801 to 25950) (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1986 Jul-1994 Nov (25951-30900) (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1994 Dec-2004 Feb (30901-37100) (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 2004 Feb-2009 May (37101-39540) (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Audio-Visual Cassette and Disc Accession Book, 1979-2009 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - CORRESPONDENCE, 1944-1996
    - 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - BRIMMER, ALTON Correspondence Files [not received], 1955
    - 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Kopanic, 1970-1973 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Gillette, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - 1984-1984 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - 2001 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - 2002 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - 2003 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - 2004 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - 2005 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - 2006 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - 2007 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - 2008 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - 2009 (Box 2, Folder 52)
- Drama Library gift records, 1944-2008; Accession 2010-A-004; 0.75
  Restricted to office of origin only.
  The materials consist of correspondence and related materials documenting gifts to the Drama Library.
  - Gift records
    - TRUE AND SPECIAL FRIEND Gifts from us & book list, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: gifts and offers to purchase, 1944-1955 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Brodkin Gift, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Matlock Gift, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Oenslager Material, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Sircom Gift, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Sperling gifts, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - James Carroll Gifts, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - John Carraro Gifts, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - 1998 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - 2001 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - 2002 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - 2003 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - 2004 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - 2005 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - 2006 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - 2007 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - 2008 (Box 2, Folder 44)